taggle.com 2011-11-04

# Your privacy is very important to us. Here is the policy governing your privacy and personal information on the Taggle service.

Taggle Internet Ventures Private Limited ('Taggle', 'We', 'Our', 'Us') is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring you have a positive experience on our website, www.taggle.com ("Website"). This policy outlines our personal information handling practices for both online and offline data. If you give us personal information, we will treat it according to this policy. By accessing or using our Website and other services from Taggle, you acknowledge that you have read and agree to be bound to the terms of this Privacy Policy and Website Terms of Use

We encourage you to read this policy to ensure you understand Taggle's privacy practices.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you by means of a notice on our home page. By continuing to use the Taggle service after notice of changes have been published on the Website, you are consenting to the changes.

**1.     ****Personal Information collected:**

Taggle leverages collaboration, networking and technology to enable a group buying model for various services. _We advise you that if you do not wish to have your information used or displayed as described in the privacy policy and User Agreement, you should reconsider becoming a member or user of Taggle. You willingly provide us certain personal information, which we collect in order to provide Taggle services. If you have any hesitation about providing such information to us and/or having such information displayed on the Taggle website or otherwise used in any manner permitted in this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, you should not register as a Member on the Website or use any of our services._

We collect your personal information in the following ways:

a. _Registration:_

When you register on Taggle and create an account you are required to provide the following information, which you recognize and expressly acknowledge is personal information allowing others, including Taggle, to identify you: name, User ID, email address, country, ZIP/postal code, age, date of birth, phone number, password chosen by you and valid financial account information. Other information requested on our Registration page, including the ability to receive promotional offers. We may, in future, include other optional requests for information from you to help us to customize the Website to deliver personalized information to you. Without your agreement, we will not share, rent or sell any personal information with third parties in any way other than what is disclosed in this privacy statement. To process your order of purchase of products or services, we require a valid credit card number, validity period and name as it appears on the credit card. Credit card information is transmitted via a minimum of 128-bit encryption for your protection. Information listed above in some cases may be mandatory, depending upon the nature of Taggle Services you have chosen.

For the purpose of making Taggle's offers and services customised to your needs we may also choose to request you to provide us with details of your friends and family. The same will be used by us to market our services.

b. _Referral Programs:_

Taggle's programs may require you to refer Taggle's Services to your friends and relatives. We might collect some of the personally identifiable information such as name, email id etc. to provide you services under the referral program.

_c. Taggle Payment System_

Our Payment Service requires Members/users to pay with a credit card,debit card, internet banking, or cash card. We will collect your credit card number and/or other financial institution information such as bank account numbers and will use that information for the billing and payment processes, including but not limited to the use and disclosure of such credit card number and information to third parties as necessary to complete such billing operation. Verification of credit information, however, is accomplished solely by the User through the authentication process. We will share your personal information as necessary for third parties to provide some of these services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes

_d. Log files, IP addresses and information about your computer_

Due to the communications standards on the Internet, when you visit the Taggle Website we automatically receive the URL of the site from which you came . We also receive the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), your computer operating system and type of web browser you are using, email patterns, as well as the name of your ISP. This information is used to analyze overall trends to help us improve the Taggle service. The linkage between your IP address and your personally identifiable information is not shared with third-parties without your permission or except when required by law. 

_e. Cookies and Web Beacons_

Like most websites, Taggle uses cookies and web log files to track site usage. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing User preferences and tracking User trends. In the course of serving advertisements or optimizing services to our Users, we may allow authorized third parties to place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. Taggle does not store personally identifiable information in the cookies.

We allow other companies, to serve advertisements to Users. These companies include third party ad servers, ad agencies, ad technology vendors and research firms. Taggle may "target" some ads to Users that fit a certain general profile. Taggle does NOT use personally identifiable information to target ads.

_f. Processing information about you and modification of such information_

All the information you provide Taggle, including sensitive personal information, is voluntary. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, but please note that your withdrawal of consent will not be retroactive.

You can access, modify, correct and eliminate the data about you which has been collected pursuant to your decision to become a User. If you update any of your information, we may keep a copy of the information which you originally provided to us in our archives for uses documented herein. We take your rights seriously and encourage you to use them if you deem this to be appropriate. You may exercise these rights by emailing us at [privacy@taggle.com](mailto:privacy@taggle.com).

_g. External links._

This Privacy Policy applies to web sites and services that are owned and operated by Taggle. We do not exercise control over the sites displayed as search results or links from within our various services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you, for which Taggle is not responsible or liable. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of that website.

**2.     ****Uses of Personal Information:**

We will not share your Personally Identifiable Information with other parties except as provided below. Other information, that does not personally identify you as an individual, is collected by Taggle from Users (such as, patterns of utilization described above) and is exclusively owned by Taggle. This information can be utilized by Taggle in such manner as Taggle, in its sole discretion, deems appropriate.

_a. Sharing your information with Taggle Merchants_ : 

For example, if you purchase a product or service from our Website, we will have to provide some of the Personally Identifiable Information like your Name and other details to the Merchant in order to process your request. We specifically disclaim any responsibility or liability for the actions of Taggle Merchant. While we inform them that they are only permitted to communicate with you for the purposes of the specific promotion with Taggle, we do not have any responsibility for the actions of the Taggle Merchant, and the actions of the Taggle Merchant are not in our control.

_b. Sharing your information with authorized third party service providers and business partners:_

We provide some of our services and products through third parties and business partners. These parties provide various services including sending out and distributing our administrative and promotional messages on web or mobile or other media, embedding the Website URL on their website, sending customer traffic to the Website, and other business affiliation. We may share your Personally Identifiable Information with such parties to fulfil orders, deliver packages, send post or email, administer contests or sweepstakes, remove repetitive information on customer lists, analyze data, provide marketing assistance, provide search results and links, process credit card payments, operate the Website, troubleshoot, and provide customer service. We may also collect personal information from individuals and companies ("Affiliates") with whom we have business relationships and may have to also share their information with Service Providers to accomplish our administrative tasks. For example, when you order a service, we release your credit card information to the card-issuing bank to confirm payment for the service and, if applicable, release your address to the delivery service to deliver the service. Likewise, we may release an Affiliate's information to our bank to send out a payment. We encourage Taggle Merchants and Third Party Service Providers and business partners to adopt and post privacy policies on their website. However, the use of your Personally Identifiable Information by such parties is governed by the privacy policies of such parties and is not subject to our control.

_c. Communication and Update_

Taggle will communicate with you through email, mobile messages, and notices posted on the Taggle Website or through other means available through the service, including text and other forms of messaging. You can change your contact preferences at any time by logging into Taggle and change the account settings or emailing Taggle at care@taggle.com.

_d. Surveys, Contests and Polls_

At times, Taggle conducts a User survey to collect information about our Users' preferences. These surveys are optional and if you choose to respond, your responses will be kept anonymous. Similarly, we may offer contests to qualifying Users in which we ask for contact and demographic information such as name, email address and mailing address. None of this information is shared with third parties, except in summary form, if at all. The demographic information that Taggle collects in the registration process and through surveys is used to help us improve our Services to meet the needs and preferences of our Users. This may include targeting advertising to you about our Services. Information we gather through a contest may also be disclosed to third parties, as necessary, for prize fulfilment and other aspects of any contest or similar offering.

e. Testimonials

We may chose to use testimonials/ feedback provided by you by email or on our website for marketing purposes. By making any suggestions, feedback or comments on Taggle, its people and services you have agreed to allow Taggle to publish the same for marketing purposes by Taggle

_f. Legal Disclaimer_

It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information when required by law, such as responses to civil or criminal subpoenas, or other requests by law enforcement personnel. We will disclose such information wherein we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, subpoena, or other legal process or request to Taggle brought in any country throughout the world, or to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

_g. Disclosures to others_

We may also disclose your personal and other information you provide, to another third party as part of a reorganization or a sale of the assets of a Taggle corporation division or company. Any third party to which we transfer or sell Taggle' assets will have the right to continue to use the personal and other information that you provide to us.

_h. Other uses:_

.         Providing our products and services to users, including the display of customized content and advertising; 

.         Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services; 

.         Ensuring the technical functioning of our network; and 

.         Developing new services. 

_i. Disclosure of non-personally identifiable information:_

We may disclose or share non-personally identifiable information with partners, affiliates and advertisers. For example, we may share aggregated demographic information (which does not include any personally identifiable information) with third party advertisers and other parties as provided below:

We use third party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use such information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide, through the use of network tags, advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. We may track and analyze Website usage and other statistical information to administer our Website and constantly improve its quality. We may also publish this information for promotional purposes or as a representative audience for advertisers. 

**3.     ****Your choice in managing your information**

_a. Closing your account_

You can also close your account on Taggle. On closure, we will remove your name and other personally identifiable information from our database. We may retain certain data contributed by you if we believe it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, or for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by law. To request that we close your account and remove your information from the website, please send your request to [care@taggle.com](mailto:care@taggle.com) with the subject "Remove Account".

We encourage you to promptly update your personally identifiable information if it changes. You may ask to have the information on your account deleted or removed; however, because we keep track of past transactions, you cannot delete information associated with past transactions on the Website. In addition, in may be impossible for us to completely delete all of your information because we periodically backup information.

_b. Retrieval of information_

Taggle internally has a process on information security and your information being accessed only by those who are authorised. In situations where you accidentally delete your information and would like to retrieve, then this core team may access the stored database and recover the same. Please be aware that this team may have to go through your personal information in order to restore the information sought by you.

_c. Other Administrative activities_

As a condition of purchase of our products and services, we will send you administrative and promotional emails or mobile messages. We will send you information regarding your account activity and purchases as well as updates about our products and promotional offers. You cannot opt-out of administrative emails or mobile messages. "Administrative Emails or mobile messages" relate to a User's activity on the Website, and include emails/mobile messages regarding a particular User's account, requests or inquiries, and purchases of products and services. In contrast to Administrative Emails or mobile messages, however, you do have a choice with respect to Promotional Emails and mobile messages. Promotional Emails/mobile messages advertise our products and services, including exclusive sales and other offers, and/or the products and services of our Advertisers and Affiliates. If you do not want to receive Promotional messages from us, you may elect to opt-out at any time by visiting the website, by e-mailing us at [care@taggle.com](mailto:care@taggle.com), by writing to us at the address contained herein, or by hitting the "unsubscribe" button at the bottom of any of our e-mails. When contacting us, please indicate your name, address, email address, mobile number and what Promotional Messages you do not want to receive.

**4\. Minors**

Children below 18 years are not eligible to use our service and we hereby request children below this age group not to submit any personal information to us or use the service. If you are under 18, you may use Taggle Services only with the Direct involvement and under the supervision of a parent or guardian.

**5\. Information Security**

We take security seriously and take numerous precautions to protect the security of personally identifiable information. You can access your personally identifiable information on our Website through a password and your email address. This password is encrypted. We recommend that you do not share your password with anyone. In addition, your Personally Identifiable Information resides on a secure server that only selected personnel and contractors have access to.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we employ commercially reasonable security measures to protect data and seek to partner with companies which do the same, we cannot guarantee the security of any information transmitted to or from the Website, and are not responsible for the actions of any third parties that may receive any such information

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data.

**6\. Users Obligations**

As a User, you have certain obligations toward the other Users with whom you will be communicating. Certain of these obligations are imposed by applicable law and regulations, and others have become commonplace in user-friendly communities of like-minded member. 

a. You must, at all times, respect the terms and conditions of the then-current Privacy Policy and the User Agreement. This includes respecting all intellectual property rights which may belong to third parties. 

b. You must not download or otherwise disseminate any information which may be deemed to be injurious, violent, offensive, racist or xenophobic or which may otherwise violate the purpose and spirit of Taggle and its community of Users. 

c. You must not provide information to Taggle and /or other Users which you believe might be injurious or detrimental to your person, professional or social status. 

Any violation of these guidelines may lead to the restriction, suspension or termination of your account by Taggle, as we take these principles seriously and consider them to be the basis on which our Users adhere to the Taggle Website and the services which it offers

**7\. Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Taggle may update this privacy policy at any time, with or without advance notice. In the event there are significant changes in the way we treat your personally identifiable information, we will display a notice on the website or send you an email, as provided for above. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.

If you use the Taggle service after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on our site, you hereby provide your consent to the changed practices.

**8\. Contact details.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us through our website by clicking the "contact us" link.

Last update : June 11, 2010
